Sculpture Photograph Collection: Austria-Israel
Yale University Arts Library
Sculpture Photograph Collection: Austria-Israel
1900-2005
VRC 5.2
Yale University Arts Library
30
71 boxes (Boxes 82-152 of 265)
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of sculpture. This section covers the later medieval to modern periods in European and other countries, alphabetically from Austria to Israel. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
In this section, the photographs are arranged by country. Subdivided by artist.
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of sculpture. This section covers the later medieval to modern periods in European and other countries, alphabetically from Austria to Israel. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders.
Sculpture; Photographs; Reproductions
- Austria (Box 82)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes two folders of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Anonymous artists., 22 (Box 82)
  - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 13 (Box 82)
    - School of Niklas Gerhaert of Leyden, active 1462., 1 (Box 82)
    - Guggenbichler, Johann Meinrad, 1649-1723., 3 (Box 82)
    - Hefele, Melchio, 1716-1768., 1 (Box 82)
    - Hrdlicka, Alfred, 1928-., 2 (Box 82)
    - Messerschmidt, Franz Xaver, 1763-1783., 3 (Box 82)
    - Schiele, Egon, 1890-1918., 2 (Box 82)
    - Schwarzkogler, Rudolf, 1940-1969., 1 (Box 82)
  - Individual artists, A-Z., 29 (Box 82)
    - Master of the Zwettl Altar, active 1519., 9 (Box 82)
    - Wotruba, Fritz, 1907-1975., 20 (Box 82)
- Belgium (Box 82)
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Anonymous artists., 1 (Box 82)
  - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 13 (Box 82)
    - Bury, Pol, 1922-., 3 (Box 82)
    - Magritte, Rene, 1898-1976., 4 (Box 82)
    - Meunier, Constantin, 1831-1905., 6 (Box 82)
- Britain (Box 83)
  - Anonymous artists., 93 (Box 83)
    - Miscellaneous works., 4 (Box 83)
    - XI Century., 2 (Box 83)
    - XII Century., 7 (Box 83)
    - XIII Century., 5 (Box 83)
    - XIV Century., 9 (Box 83)
    - XV Century., 41 (Box 83)
    - XVI Century., 15 (Box 84)
    - XVII and XVIII Centuries., 10 (Box 84)
  - Known Artists., 332 (Box 85)
    - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 83 (Box 85)
      - Ady, Thomas, active 1732-1752., 2 (Box 85)
      - Allwood, Walter, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 85)
      - Andras, Catherine, XVIII-XIX C., 1 (Box 85)
      - Bacon, John, 1740-1799., 2 (Box 85)
      - Baker, Percy Bryant, 1881-1970., 2 (Box 85)
      - Banks, Thomas, 1735-1805., 3 (Box 85)
      - Bates, Henry, 1850-1899., 1 (Box 85)
      - Chadwick, Lynn, 1914-., 2 (Box 85)
      - Cheverton, B., 1794-1876., 1 (Box 85)
      - Dadswell, Lynden, 1908-., 1 (Box 85)
      - Dick, Reid, 1879-1961., 1 (Box 85)
      - Durst, Alan, 1883-1970., 1 (Box 85)
      - Dwight, John, ?., 1 (Box 85)
      - Emerson, R. J., XX C., 1 (Box 85)
      - Evans, David, XX C., 1 (Box 85)
      - Evans, Garth, 1934-., 2 (Box 85)
      - Ford, Onslow, 1852-1901., 1 (Box 85)
      - Francis, John, 1780-1861., 1 (Box 85)
      - Frink, Elisabeth, 1930-1993., 2 (Box 85)
      - Garbe, Richard, 1876-1957., 1 (Box 85)
      - Gibbons, Grinling, 1648-1721., 2 (Box 85)
      - Gibson, John, 1817-1892., 1 (Box 85)
        Photo is only marked as "Gibson, but the style looks correct for John Gibson s period.
      - Gilbert and George, XX C., 1 (Box 85)
      - Gillick, Ernest, XX C., 1 (Box 85)
      - Gower, Ronald Sutherland, Lord, 1845-1916., 1 (Box 85)
      - Grinling, A Gibbons, 1896-., 1 (Box 85)
      - Hampton, Herbert, 1862-?., 1 (Box 85)
      - Hardiman, Alfred F., XIX-XX C., 2 (Box 85)
      - Hartwell, Charles L., 1873-1951., 1 (Box 85)
      - Hewetson, Christopher, c.1739-1798/9., 1 (Box 85)
      - Hodge, John, XX C.?., 1 (Box 85)
      - Hoff, Raynor, 1894-1937., 1 (Box 85)
      - Huxley-Jones, Thomas b., 1908-., 1 (Box 85)
      - Jagger, Charles S., 1885-1934., 1 (Box 85)
      - Jones, Adrian, 1845-1938., 1 (Box 85)
      - Joseph, Samuel, active 1811-1850., 1 (Box 85)
      - Kapoor, Anish, 1954-., 1 (Box 85)
      - Kent, William, 1685-1748., 1 (Box 85)
      - King, Phillip, 1934-., 3 (Box 85)
      - Lambert, Maurice, 1901-1964., 1 (Box 85)
      - Ledward, Gilbert, 1888-1960., 1 (Box 85)
      - Leighton, Frederic, Lord, 1830-1896., 1 (Box 85)
      - Le Marchand, David, 1674-1726., 1 (Box 85)
      - Long, Richard, 1940-., 1 (Box 85)
      - MacGillivray, J. P., 1856-1938., 1 (Box 85)
      - Mason, Raymond, 1922-., 2 (Box 85)
      - McWilliam, F. E., 1909-., 2 (Box 85)
      - Meadows, Bernard, 1915-., 4 (Box 85)
      - Merrifield, L. S., XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 85)
      - Moore, John Francis, ?-1809., 2 (Box 85)
      - Nash, Paul, 1889-1946., 1 (Box 85)
      - Nicholson, Ben, 1894-., 1 (Box 85)
      - Nollekens, Joseph, 1737-1823., 1 (Box 85)
      - Oakley, Alfred, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 85)
      - Paolozzi, Eduardo, 1924-., 1 (Box 85)
      - Poole, Henry, 1873-1928., 1 (Box 85)
      - Poultrain, Maximilian, XVI C., 1
      - Scott, Tim, 1937-., 1 (Box 85)
      - Sparr, Elizabeth, XX C., 1 (Box 85)
      - Underwood, Leon, 1890-1975., 1 (Box 85)
      - Westmacott, Richard, 1775-1856., 2 (Box 85)
      - Woodrow, Bill, 1948-., 2 (Box 85)
      - Wyatt, ?, XIX C., 1 (Box 85)
    - Individual artists, A-Z., 249 (Box 86)
      - Armitage, Kenneth, 1916-., 5 (Box 86)
      - Butler, Reg, 1913-., 11 (Box 86)
      - Caro, Anthony, 1924-., 20 (Box 86)
      - Dobson, Frank, 1886-1963., 6 (Box 86)
      - Epstein, Jacob, 1880-1959., 46 (Box 87)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 36 (Box 87)
        - Buffalo., 2 (Box 87)
        - London., 8 (Box 87)
      - Flaxman, John, 1755-1826., 5 (Box 87)
      - Ford, Sir Edward Onslow, 1852-1901., 3 (Box 87)
      - Frampton, George J., 1860-1928., 5 (Box 87)
      - Gilbert, Alfred, 1854-1934., 5 (Box 88)
      - Gill, Eric, 1882-1940., 6 (Box 88)
      - Haseltine, Herbert, 1877-., 10 (Box 88)
      - Hepworth, Barbara, 1903-1975., 17 (Box 88)
      - Miller, Alec, XX C., 3 (Box 88)
      - Moore, Henry, 1898-1986., 94 (Box 89)
        Includes a folder of miscellaneous works.
        - Miscellaneous works., 23 (Box 89)
        - 1930-1939., 15 (Box 89)
        - 1940-1949., 18 (Box 89)
        - 1950-1959., 25 (Box 89)
        - 1960-1969., 13 (Box 89)
      - Stevens, Alfred, 1817-1875., 8 (Box 90)
      - Wilton, Joseph, 1722-1803., 5 (Box 90)
- Bulgaria. (Box 91)
  - Individual artists, A-Z., 20 (Box 91)
    - Christo, 1935-., 20 (Box 91)
      First name: Javacheff.
- Czechoslovakia (Box 91)
  - Individual artists, A-Z., 1
    - Gutfreund, Otto, 1889-1927., 1 (Box 91)
- Denmark (Box 91)
  - Anonymous artists., 6
  - Individual artists, A-Z., 43 (Box 91)
    - Heide, Henning von der, XVI C., 1 (Box 91)
    - Moeller-Nielsen, Egon, XX C., 1 (Box 91)
    - Poulsen, Axel, 1887-., 1 (Box 91)
    - Thorwaldsen, Bertel, 1770-1844., 40 (Box 91)
- Flanders (Box 92)
  - Anonymous artists., 36 (Box 92)
    - XI to XIV Century., 9 (Box 92)
    - XV Century., 17 (Box 92)
    - XVI Century., 10 (Box 92)
  - Miscellaneous artists, A-Z., 16 (Box 92)
    - Borman, Jan, active 1479-1520., 3 (Box 92)
    - Candido, Pietro, 1548-1586., 1 (Box 92)
    - Duquesnoy, Francois, 1594-1643., 2 (Box 92)
    - Faydherbe, Lucas, 1617-1697., 1 (Box 92)
    - Kerricx, Guillaume, 1652-1719., 1 (Box 92)
    - Quellinus, Artus, 1609-1668., 1 (Box 92)
    - Quellinus II, Artus, 1625-1700., 1 (Box 92)
    - Rysback, John Michael, 1693-1770., 1 (Box 92)
    - Scheemakers, Peter, 1691-1781., 2 (Box 92)
    - Tassaert, Jean Pierre Antoine, 1724-1788., 3 (Box 92)
    - Van der Voort, Michiel, 1667-1737., 1 (Box 92)
  - Individual artists, A-Z., 17 (Box 92)
    - Renier de Huy, active 1107-1118., 7 (Box 92)
    - Rysbrack, John Michael, 1693-1770., 5 (Box 92)
    - Verhelst, Aegidius the Elder, 1696-1749., 5 (Box 92)
- France (Box 93)
  - Anonymous artists., 766 (Box 93)
    - Romanesque., 37 (Box 93)
      Includes two folders of miscellaneous works.
      - Miscellaneous works., 24 (Box 93)
      - Capitals., 13 (Box 93)
    - XI Century., 18 (Box 93)
    - XII Century., 135 (Box 94)
      - Miscellaneous works., 16 (Box 94)
      - Capitals., 31 (Box 94)
      - Figures., 61 (Box 94)
        - Miscellaneous works., 18 (Box 94)
        - Virgin and child., 18 (Box 95)
        - Virgin and child with saints, from St. Martin, Angers., 25 (Box 95)
      - Heads., 13 (Box 95)
      - Reliefs., 14 (Box 95)
    - XIII Century., 83 (Box 96)
      - Miscellaneous works., 8 (Box 96)
      - Choir stalls, Notre Dame, Paris., 8 (Box 96)
      - Figures., 54 (Box 96)
        - Miscellaneous works., 28 (Box 96)
        - Virgin and child., 26 (Box 97)
      - Gravestones and tombs., 5 (Box 97)
      - Heads., 8 (Box 97)
    - XIV Century., 144 (Box 98)
      - Miscellaneous works., 3 (Box 98)
      - Figures., 88 (Box 98)
        - Miscellaneous works and groups of figures., 9 (Box 98)
        - Female., 19 (Box 98)
        - Male., 20 (Box 98)
        - Virgin and child., 40 (Box 99)
      - Heads., 8 (Box 99)
      - Tombs., 45 (Box 100)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 5 (Box 100)
        - S. Denis, Abbey., 40 (Box 100)
          - Miscellaneous tombs., 30 (Box 100)
          - Blanche de, Evreux and Jeanne de France., 5 (Box 100)
          - Philippe V and Jeanne d Evreux., 5 (Box 100)
    - XV Century., 151 (Box 101)
      - Miscellaneous works., 14 (Box 101)
      - Figures., 83 (Box 101)
        - Miscellaneous works., 1 (Box 101)
        - Female., 17 (Box 101)
        - Male., 40 (Box 101)
        - Virgin and child., 25 (Box 102)
      - Groups., 30 (Box 102)
        - Miscellaneous works., 19 (Box 102)
        - Solesmes, Burial of Christ., 7 (Box 102)
        - Pietas., 4 (Box 102)
      - Heads., 13 (Box 103)
      - Tombs., 11 (Box 103)
    - XVI Century., 146 (Box 104)
      - Miscellaneous works., 12 (Box 104)
      - Busts., 10 (Box 104)
      - Figures., 32 (Box 104)
        - Miscellaneous works., 24 (Box 104)
        - Virgin and child., 8 (Box 104)
      - Groups., 18 (Box 104)
      - Misericordia and choir stalls., 52 (Box 105)
        - Miscellaneous locations., 22 (Box 105)
        - Amiens., 22 (Box 105)
        - Chateau de Pagny., 8 (Box 105)
      - Retables., 9 (Box 105)
      - Tombs., 13 (Box 105)
    - XVII Century., 20 (Box 106)
    - XVIII Century., 27 (Box 106)
    - XIX to XX Century., 5 (Box 106)
  - Known Artists., 1381 (Box 107)
    - A, 40 (Box 107)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 3 (Box 107)
        - Abel, Marie, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 107)
        - Arnoux, Claude, active c. 1545-1578., 1 (Box 107)
        - Attiret, Claude-Francois, 1728-1804., 1 (Box 107)
      - Individual Artists., 37 (Box 107)
        - Adam, Lambert Sigisbert, 1700-1759., 3 (Box 107)
        - Anguier, Michel, 1612-1686., 4 (Box 107)
        - Arman, Fernandez, 1928-., 5 (Box 107)
        - Arp, Jean, 1887-1966., 25 (Box 107)
          Also known as Hans Arp.
    - B, 125 (Box 108)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 17 (Box 108)
        - Barreau, G., XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 108)
        - Barrias, Louis, 1841-1905., 1 (Box 108)
        - Barrois, Francois, 1656-1726., 1 (Box 108)
        - Beauneveu, Andre, 1360-1403., 3 (Box 108)
        - Becquet, Just, 1829-1907., 1 (Box 108)
        - Bernhard, Sarah, XIX C., 1 (Box 108)
        - Berruer, Pierre Francois, 1733-1797., 1 (Box 108)
        - Bonnard, Pierre, 1867-1947., 1 (Box 108)
        - Bosio, Baron Francois Joseph, 1768-1846., 1 (Box 108)
        - Bouchard, Henry, 1875-1960., 1 (Box 108)
        - Boucher, Jean, 1870-., 1 (Box 108)
        - Bourdelle, Antoine, 1861-1929., 1 (Box 108)
        - Bourdin, Michel, -1623., 1 (Box 108)
        - Buchet, Gustav, 1888-1963., 1 (Box 108)
        - Buren, Daniel, 1938-., 1 (Box 108)
      - Individual Artists., 108 (Box 108)
        - Bartholdi, Frederic Auguste, 1834-1904., 2 (Box 108)
        - Bartholome, Albert, 1848-1928., 3 (Box 108)
        - Barye, Antoine Louis, 1796-1875., 37 (Box 108)
        - Baschet, Bernard and Francois, XX C., 4 (Box 108)
        - Beauneveu, Andre, 1360-1403., 8 (Box 108)
        - Bernard, Joseph, 1866-1931., 3 (Box 109)
        - Blassel, Nicolas the Younger, 1600-1659., 4 (Box 109)
        - Boizot, Simon-Louis, 1743-1809., 3 (Box 109)
        - Bontemps, Pierre, active 1536-1562., 7 (Box 109)
        - Bouchardon, Edme, 1698-1762., 11 (Box 109)
        - Bourdelle, Antoine Emile, 1861-1929., 23 (Box 109)
        - Braques, Georges, 1882-1963., 3 (Box 109)
    - C, 222 (Box 110)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 18 (Box 110)
        - Carlier, C. M. L., 1904-1930., 1 (Box 110)
        - Carrier-Belleuse, Albert-Ernst, 1824-1887., 2 (Box 110)
        - Cavelier, Paul-Jules, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 110)
        - Cesar, 1921-., 2 (Box 110)
        - Chastel, XVI C.?, 1 (Box 110)
        - Chaudet, Antoine, 1763-1810., 2 (Box 110)
        - Chiparus, Dimitri, active 1914-1928., 1 (Box 110)
        - Christophe, E., 1827-1892., 1 (Box 110)
        - Cleeve, Corneille van, 1646-1732., 1 (Box 110)
        - Collot, Marie Anne, 1748-1821., 1 (Box 110)
        - Cortot, Jean Pierre, 1787-1843., 2 (Box 110)
        - Coustou, Nicolas, 1658-1733., 1 (Box 110)
        - Coutan, Jules Felix, 1848-1939., 1 (Box 110)
        - Couturier, Robert, 1905-., 1 (Box 110)
      - Individual Artists., 204 (Box 110)
        - Caffieri, Jean Jacques, 1725-1792., 14 (Box 110)
        - Carpeaux, Jean Baptiste, 1827-1875., 50 (Box 110)
          - Miscellaneous works., 23 (Box 110)
          - The Dance., 27 (Box 110)
        - Chapu, Henri, 1833-1891., 3 (Box 111)
        - Chinard, Jean, XIX-XX C., 2 (Box 111)
        - Chinard, Joseph, 1756-1813., 3 (Box 111)
        - Clodion, Claude Michel, 1738-1814., 49 (Box 111)
        - Colombe, Michel, 1430-1512., 15 (Box 111)
        - Cordier, Charles Henri-Joseph, 1827-1905., 5 (Box 112)
        - Cousin, Jean, c.1500-1590., 2 (Box 112)
        - Coustou, Guillaume the Elder, 1677-1746., 22 (Box 112)
        - Coysevox, Antoine, 1640-1720., 39 (Box 112)
    - D, 141 (Box 113)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 20 (Box 113)
        - Dampt, J. A., 1854-1919., 1 (Box 113)
        - Darde, Paul, XIX-XX C., 2 (Box 113)
        - David, Adolphe, 1828-1876., 1 (Box 113)
        - Delaplanche, Eugene, 1836-1891., 3 (Box 113)
        - Derbais, Jerome, 1668-1715., 1 (Box 113)
        - Desbois, Jules, 1851-1935., 1 (Box 113)
        - Desjardins, Martin, 1639/40-1694., 1 (Box 113)
        - De Soete, Pierre, XX C., 1 (Box 113)
        - De Vries, Adrien, 1545-1626., 1 (Box 113)
        - De Wilde, B. and T., XVIII C., 1 (Box 113)
        - Dore, Gustave, 1832-1883., 1 (Box 113)
        - Drivier, Leon, 1878-1951., 1 (Box 113)
        - Dubuffet, Jean, 1901-1985., 3 (Box 113)
        - Dumont, Jacques-Edme, 1720-1775., 1 (Box 113)
        - Duplessis, J. S., 1725-1802., 1 (Box 113)
        - Dupre, Guillaume, 1576-1643., 1 (Box 113)
      - Individual Artists., 121 (Box 113)
        - Dalou, Jules, 1838-1902., 3 (Box 113)
        - David d Angers, Pierre Jean, 1788-1856., 4 (Box 113)
        - Dantan, Jean-Pierre, 1800-1869., 1 (Box 113)
        - Daumier, Honore, 1808-1879., 6 (Box 113)
        - Degas, Edgar, 1834-1917., 35 (Box 113)
        - Derain, Andre, 1880-1954., 2 (Box 113)
        - Despiau, Charles, 1874-1946., 29 (Box 114)
        - DuBois, Paul, 1829-1905., 3 (Box 114)
        - Duchamp, Marcel, 1887-1968., 29 (Box 114)
        - Duchamp-Villon, Raymond, 1876-1918., 9 (Box 114)
    - E, 2 (Box 115)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 2 (Box 115)
        - Erte, 1892-1990., 2 (Box 115)
    - F, 40 (Box 115)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 4 (Box 115)
        - Feitu, Pierre, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 115)
        - Francheville, Pierre de, 1554-1615., 2 (Box 115)
        - Fresnaye, Roger de la, 1885-1925., 1 (Box 115)
      - Individual Artists., 36 (Box 115)
        - Falconet, Etienne, 1716-1791., 26 (Box 115)
        - Falguiere, Alexandre, 1831-1900., 2 (Box 115)
        - Fremiet, Emmanuel, 1824-1911., 8 (Box 115)
    - G, 107 (Box 116)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 12 (Box 116)
        - Gaugnie, XIX C., 1 (Box 116)
        - Gilis, A., XVIII C., 1 (Box 116)
        - Gorin, Jean, 1899-1981., 1 (Box 116)
        - Goulon, Jules du, active 1698-c.1729., 1 (Box 116)
        - Granier, Pierre, 1635-1715., 2 (Box 116)
        - Guerin, Gilles, 1606-1678., 2 (Box 116)
        - Guillaume, Eugene, 1822-1905., 1 (Box 116)
        - Guilleaume, Emil, XX C., 1 (Box 116)
        - Guino, Michel, 1926-., 1 (Box 116)
        - Guybert, Nicolas, active 1542., 1 (Box 116)
      - Individual Artists., 95 (Box 116)
        - Gaudier-Brzeska, Henri, 1891-1915., 16 (Box 116)
        - Gauguin, Paul, 1848-1903., 17 (Box 116)
        - Gerome, Jean-Leon, 1824-1904., 8 (Box 116)
        - Gimond, Marcel Antoine, 1894-., 2 (Box 116)
        - Girardon, Francois, 1628-1715., 22 (Box 117)
        - Goujon, Jean, 1515-1564/5., 23 (Box 117)
        - Gregoire, ?, XVIII C.?, 3 (Box 117)
        - Guillain, Simon, 1581-1658., 4 (Box 117)
    - H, 108 (Box 118)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 2 (Box 118)
        - Haber, ?, XX C., 1 (Box 118)
        - Hajdu, Etienne, 1907-., 1 (Box 118)
      - Individual Artists., 106 (Box 118)
        - Houdon, Jean Antoine, 1741-1828., 106 (Box 118)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 58 (Box 118, Box 30)
          - Berlin., 6 (Box 119)
          - New Haven., 11 (Box 119)
          - New York., 8 (Box 119)
          - Paris., 13 (Box 119)
          - Philadelphia., 10 (Box 119)
    - I, J, K, 26 (Box 119)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 5 (Box 119)
        - Janniot, Alfred Auguste, 1889-1969., 1 (Box 119)
        - Jouffroy, Francois, 1806-1882., 1 (Box 119)
        - Julien, Pierre, 1731-1804., 1 (Box 119)
        - Klein, Yves, 1928-1962., 2 (Box 119)
      - Individual Artists., 21 (Box 119)
        - Jean de Cambrai, -1438., 6 (Box 119)
        - Jean de Liege, -1382., 3 (Box 119)
        - Juste, Jean the Elder, 1485-1549, and Antoine, 1479-1519., 9 (Box 119)
        - Knoop, Guitou, XX C., 3 (Box 119)
    - L, 97 (Box 120)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 11 (Box 120)
        - Ladatte, Francesco, 1706-1787., 1 (Box 120)
        - Lanson, Alfred D., 1851-?., 1 (Box 120)
        - Leger, Ferdinand, 1881-1955., 2 (Box 120)
        - Le Gros, Pierre II, 1666-1719., 1 (Box 120)
        - Le Lorrain, Louis Jourdan, 1715-1759., 1 (Box 120)
        - Lemire, Antoine, 1773-1827., 1 (Box 120)
        - Lhouste, Gabriel, active c.1533-1558., 1 (Box 120)
        - Lipsi, Maurice, 1897-., 1 (Box 120)
        - Loisel, Robert, active 1382-1408., 2 (Box 120)
          Works done with Thomas Prive, 1389-1397.
      - Individual Artists., 86 (Box 120)
        - Landowski, Paul, 1875-1961., 5 (Box 120)
        - Laurens, Henri, 1885-1954., 12 (Box 120)
        - Le Comte, Felix, 1737-1817., 2 (Box 120)
        - Le Lorrain, Robert, 1666-1743., 6 (Box 120)
        - Lemoyne, Jean-Baptiste, 1704-1778., 11 (Box 120)
        - Lemoyne, Jean-Louise, 1665-1755., 7 (Box 121)
        - Le Pautre, Pierre, 1660-1744., 2 (Box 121)
        - Leroux, Roulland, active 1509, d. 1527., 3 (Box 121)
        - Le Sueur, Hubert, c.1580-1643?, 5 (Box 121)
        - Lipchitz, Jacques, 1891-1973., 34 (Box 121)
    - M, 139 (Box 122)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 19 (Box 122)
        - Magnier, Philippe, 1618-1700., 1 (Box 122)
        - Maillet, Jacques Leonard, 1823-1895., 1 (Box 122)
        - Marchand, Francois, active 1541-1553., 1 (Box 122)
        - Marin, Joseph Charles, 1759-1834., 3 (Box 122)
        - Marochetti, Carlo, 1805-1867., 1 (Box 122)
        - Martel, Joel, active 1932., 1 (Box 122)
        - Martin, Etienne, XX C., 1 (Box 122)
        - Mayon, F., ?., 1 (Box 122)
        - Maziere, Simon, c.1649-1720., 1 (Box 122)
        - Mignard, Pierre, 1612-1695., 1 (Box 122)
        - Modigliani, Amedeo, 1884-1920., 1 (Box 122)
        - Moiturier, Antoine le, 1425-1497., 1 (Box 122)
        - Monnot, Pierre Etienne, 1657-1733., 1 (Box 122)
        - Moreau, Gustave, 1826-1898, 1 (Box 122)
        - Moreau-Vauthier, Augustin, 1831-1893., 2 (Box 122)
        - Morellet, Francois, 1926-., 1 (Box 122)
      - Individual Artists., 120 (Box 122)
        - Maillol, Aristide, 1861-1944., 89 (Box 122)
          - Miscellaneous works., 12 (Box 122)
          - Heads., 8 (Box 122)
          - Reclining nudes., 9 (Box 122)
          - Seated nudes., 26 (Box 122)
          - Standing nudes., 26 (Box 123)
          - Torsos., 8 (Box 123)
        - Marqueste, Laurent H., 1848-1920., 2 (Box 123)
        - Matisse, Henri, 1869-1954., 25 (Box 123)
        - Mercie, Marius Jean Antonin, 1845-1916., 4 (Box 123)
    - N, 1 (Box 123)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 1 (Box 123)
        - Nocq, Henry, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 123)
    - O, 2 (Box 123)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 2 (Box 123)
        - Orloff, Chana, 1888-1968., 1 (Box 123)
        - Ottin, Auguste Louis Marie, 1811-1890., 1 (Box 123)
    - P, 108 (Box 124)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 13 (Box 124)
        - Pattagean, ?., 1 (Box 124)
        - Pelle, Honore, XVII C., 1 (Box 124)
        - Peyrissac, Jean, 1895-., 1 (Box 124)
        - Pilon, Louis Jacques, XVIII C., 1 (Box 124)
        - Poirier, Anne, 1941-, and Patrick, 1942-., 3 (Box 124)
        - Poisson, Pierre, XX C., 1 (Box 124)
        - Pompon, Francois, 1855-1933., 2 (Box 124)
        - Prieur, Barthelemy, c.1540-1611., 2 (Box 124)
        - Puech, Denis, 1854-1942., 1 (Box 124)
      - Individual Artists., 95 (Box 124)
        - Pajou, Augustin, 1730-1809., 15 (Box 124)
        - Paulin, Paul, active 1882-1922., 4 (Box 124)
        - Pepin de Huy, Jean, c.1311-1382., 4 (Box 124)
        - Pigalle, Jean Baptiste, 1714-1785., 19 (Box 124)
        - Pilon, Germain, 1535-1590., 25 (Box 125)
        - Prou, Jacques, 1655-1706., 18 (Box 125)
        - Puget, Pierre, 1622-1694., 10 (Box 125)
    - Q, 2 (Box 125)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 2 (Box 125)
        - Queisnard, P., ?., 1 (Box 125)
        - Quillivic, Rene, 1879-., 1 (Box 125)
    - R, 150 (Box 126)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 4 (Box 126)
        - Regnault, G., 1450-1531/3., 1 (Box 126)
        - Renard, Jacques, baroque., 1 (Box 126)
        - Riss, Francois, 1804-1866., 1 (Box 126)
        - Riviere, Theodore, 1857-1912., 1 (Box 126)
      - Individual Artists., 146 (Box 126)
        - Renoir, Auguste, 1841-1919., 12 (Box 126)
        - Richier, Germaine, 1904-1959., 6 (Box 126)
        - Richier, Ligier, c.1500-1567., 13 (Box 126)
        - Rodin, Auguste, 1840-1917., 99 (Box 127)
          - Miscellaneous works., 68 (Box 127)
          - Age of Bronze., 7 (Box 128)
          - Balzac., 11 (Box 128)
          - The Burghers of Calais., 8 (Box 128)
          - Thinker., 5 (Box 128)
        - Roubiliac, Louis Francois, 1705-1762., 7 (Box 128)
        - Rude, Francois, 1784-1855., 9 (Box 128)
    - S, 65 (Box 129)
      - Miscellaneous Artists., 9 (Box 129)
        - Sarabezalles, XIX-XX C., 1 (Box 129)
        - Sauvage, Henri, 1873-1932., 1 (Box 129)
        - Schoenewerk, Alexandre, 1820-1885., 2 (Box 129)
        - Schoffer, Nicolas, 1912-., 3 (Box 129)
        - Slodtze, Rene Michel, 1705-1764., 1 (Box 129)
        - Stahly, Francois, 1911-., 1 (Box 129)
      - Individual Artists., 56 (Box 129)
        - Saly, Jacques, 1717-1776., 3 (Box 129)
        - Sluter, Claus, and School of, XV C., 53 (Box 129)
          - Miscellaneous works., 7 (Box 129)
          - Portal, Chartreuse de Champmol., 11 (Box 129)